Here we have what are called princess seams.
Princess seams, though they're called seams, they are a seam, but they function as a dart.
That's why they're in the dart category because even though they're not called a dart, that's, that's their purpose.
The purpose of a dart as well as a princess seam is to make a garment fitted to the body based on that person's measurements.
So if you're going for industry standard sample size in all of your garments, like your first mock up of a garment, is going to be set to that sample size variation, that, that person's measurement, a fit model.
And based on that, princess seams are what you would see like on a jacket that's nipped in at the waist.
And it can, princess seams allow you, depending on where you place them, to pull it in even further or let it out a little further and just have a slight princess seam, meaning there's just a slight wider at the shoulders and down to the waist.
For princess seams, as you would see on a jacket, we will of course, neckline, shell top arms, and then these I have shown going straight down in a V all the way to the waist.
They can do that.
Or they can curve.
And if they curve more, than draw this way doesn't, totally fine.
But this is another version that I just thought of.
The typical princess seam is going to curve down and out like that and then straighten out once it gets down to the waist point.